<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FileMaker Advisor Archive on gwcoffey.com</title>
    <link>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FileMaker Advisor Archive on gwcoffey.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assemble Multi-Part Reports with FileMaker Pro 9</title>
      <link>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/assemble-multi-part-reports-with-filemaker-pro-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/assemble-multi-part-reports-with-filemaker-pro-9/</guid>
      <description>FileMaker has some pretty powerful reporting tools. You can decorate your layouts any way you see fit, control which record show, in what order, and with any particular fields arranged to your liking. You can even summarize your data in numerous ways to produce totals, subtotals, and other aggregate analysis. But until FileMaker 9, there has been one glaring restriction: A report can only show records from one table. If you want to show new products on one page, and new customers on the next, you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring Layouts to Life with Conditional Formatting</title>
      <link>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/bring-layouts-to-life-with-conditional-formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/bring-layouts-to-life-with-conditional-formatting/</guid>
      <description>FileMaker Pro 9.0 made its debut a few short weeks ago, and it seems like its ability to connect directly to corporate databases is all anyone wants to talk about. ESS is great and all, but you may be wondering how 9 helps regular FileMaker folk like us. In point of fact, 9 is chock full of fantastic new features that even the most humble database can benefit from right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Tooltips to Guide Your Users</title>
      <link>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/use-tooltips-to-guide-your-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/use-tooltips-to-guide-your-users/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve used a computer sometime in the last five years, chances are you&amp;rsquo;ve seen tooltips. These informational little boxes pop up to help you out when you point at just about anything on the computer screen, from a toolbar icon to a truncated file name (Figure 1). Tooltips are so common, in fact, that many users know to look for them whenever they&amp;rsquo;re not sure what a particular button, icon, slider, or knob will do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make the Switch from Excel to FileMaker</title>
      <link>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/make-the-switch-from-excel-to-filemaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/make-the-switch-from-excel-to-filemaker/</guid>
      <description>It seems like Microsoft Excel is installed on just about every PC in the world. As such, a lot of new FileMaker developers are already Excel wizards. In fact, many new FileMaker projects begin life as a replacement for an Excel spreadsheet that has outgrown itself. If you are an Excel star trying to wind your way through the FileMaker universe, you may be stymied at first by all the things you thought you knew that just don&amp;rsquo;t seem to apply anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Smarter Databases with Relationships</title>
      <link>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/create-smarter-databases-with-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gwcoffey.com/archive/advisor/create-smarter-databases-with-relationships/</guid>
      <description>Relationships hold a special place in the world of a database designer: They&amp;rsquo;re simultaneously your most powerful tool and the most difficult to figure out. If your first trip to FileMaker&amp;rsquo;s Relationships tab left you scratching your head, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. FileMaker goes a long way towards making relationships easy to set up, manage, and use. But the real trick is understanding the concepts behind relationship building. In this article, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to add a sprinkling of relational capability to your own FileMaker database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
